迪拜欢迎
理查德 哈蒙德
詹姆斯 梅
杰罗姆 E 克拉克森
翻译
Monica-卡 InX 17
时间轴
Monica-卡 RN
校对
Monica-卡 InX oliver Yin RN
三辆车依次为
McLaren P1 GTR，Lamborghini  Veneno Roadster，W Motors Lykan Hypersport
-大家好  -你好各位
- Hello. - Hello, everybody.
各位好 你好
Greetings. Hello.
你好
Hello.
十分感谢
Thank you so much.
谢谢 谢谢你们
Thank you. Thank you very much.
谢谢
Thank you.
十分感谢
Thank you so much,
欢迎来到TheGrandTour
and welcome to The Grand Tour,
这周我们来到了
which this week comes to you
阿拉伯联合酋长国
from the United Arab Emirates!
准确说
Specifically...
准确的说 我们在迪拜
Specifically, we are in Dubai,
这也就意味着 有史以来第一次
which means, for the first time ever,
我们是帐篷里最穷的三个人
we are the three poorest people in the tent.
-对 对 对
- Yeah. Yeah, yeah. Yeah.
我是说 看呐
I mean, look at that.
你会想 "他们是怎么把喷泉
You think, "How do they do that
做成那样的"
with all those fountains?"
我要告诉你们一个小秘密
Well, I'll let you into a little secret.
这是巴黎水
It's Perrier water.
巴黎水是一种天然有气的高级矿泉水
直喷云霄
Flinging it up into the air.
前几天我还听到一个段子
I heard another one the other day.
一个出租车司机在一天的繁忙过后
A taxi driver clearing out his cab
收拾他的车
after a hard day at work--
雨伞 手机 平常的东西
umbrella, mobile phone, usual stuff--
一根八十万英镑的金条
£800,000 gold bar.
有人落在那里了
Someone had left it in there
-甚至都没有注意到 -你会的
- and not even noticed. - You would.
注意 据说在这里
Mind you, that said, here,
你可以直接去ATM机拿金条出来
you can just go to an ATM and get gold out.
看这个 这可是台ATM机
Look at this! That's an actual ATM.
你设想一下 在凌晨两点
You know, at two o'clock in the morning,
"我一个子都没有带"
"I haven't got an ingot with me."
但是这里就没事了
But here you're fine.
你甚至还可以在这里买轮胎
You can even buy tyres here, OK?
镶满金子和钻石的那种
Which are studded with gold and diamonds.
看这个 六十万英镑一套
Look at this. £600,000 a set.
甚至连当局都很阔绰
Even the authorities are loaded.
我们选了一些当地警车的图片
We have here a selection of pictures of local police cars.
他们有大牛
They have an Aventador.
他们还有SLS
- They also have an SLS.
是的 等着瞧 他们还有一辆布加迪威龙警车
Yeah. Wait for it. They even have a Veyron police car.
是的 显然
Oh, yeah. Obviously,
-因为很有必要 -真的
- because you need that. - You actually do.
你需要那些 这很重要
You need that. It's important.
我还有一张当地救护车的照片
I've even got a photograph of a local ambulance.
看这里 一辆莲花
- Look, here it is. It's a Lotus!
不懂这个是怎么投入使用的
Not quite sure how that works.
大概你得打断患者的另外一条腿
Presumably you have to break the patient's other leg
才能把他放进去
to actually get him in there.
-是的 -接着是这里的公共交通
- Yeah. - Then there's public transport.
在英国 这是一辆公交车 没错吧
Now, OK, in the UK, this is a bus, yes?
-是的 -让我给你看看
- Yeah. - Let me show you
当地公车的一张照片
a photograph of a local bus here.
-瞧 -哇
- There you go. - Wow!
最高时速:250kph
Top speed: 155mph.
值七百万英镑 可载23人
Costs £7 million. Seats 23 people.
你致电给车主 他会过来接你
You telephone the owner. He comes and picks you up
把你带到你要去的地方
and takes you to where you want to go.
这是辆出租车
Well, that's a taxi.
-不 詹姆斯 不是的 -不是吗
- No, James. No, no, no. - Isn't it?
在迪拜的出租车长这样
A taxi in Dubai looks like this.
哦好吧 我就知道
Oh, right. Yeah, of course.
你觉得我在开玩笑吗  看"Uber"
You think I'm joking? Look, "Uber".
真的 你在这里叫Uber
Seriously, you call Uber up here,
他们会给你挑 普锐斯还是直升机
and you're given a choice-- Prius or helicopter.
哇 你要给司机评级吗
Wow! Do you get to rate the driver?
你觉得他会把手机粘在挡风玻璃上吗
Do you think he sticks his telephone on the screen
就像英国的那些普锐斯一样
like in Britain in the Prius?
"我并不算是一个飞行员
"I'm not really a pilot.
我只是在受训当水管工时顺带做这个"
I'm doing this while training to be a plumber."
"放我出去" 赶紧走
"I want to get out!" Just get out.
-我们可以开始节目了吗 -好主意
- Shall we get on with the show? - Good idea.
因为在这周的节目里
Because in our car show this week...
船长摔倒了
James falls over.
船长又摔倒了
James fall over again.
还有船长摔倒了
And James falls over.
但首先 这里有一点争议
But first, there's been a bit of an argument.
你看 船长和我最近都刚买了
You see, James and I both recently bought
五门的德国掀背车
five-door German hatchbacks.
他的是一辆宝马i3 由电力驱动
His is a BMW i3, which is powered by electricity,
而我的则是传统的大众高尔夫GTI
and mine is a conventional Volkswagen Golf GTI.
是的 也就是说我的车来自未来
Yes, meaning my car is from the future
而他的象征过去
and his is from the past,
让我显得像开化过的 而他就是一恐龙
making me enlightened and him a dinosaur.
他们就像这样吵了很久了
They have been arguing like this for a while now.
重要的是 我不怀疑
The thing is, I don't doubt
在未来电动车会很有用
that in the future electric cars will work,
但现在不行
but they don't work now.
-它们可以的 -它们不行 船长
- Well, they do. - They don't, James!
那为什么你要在你的车里
Well, why did you fit yours
装一个汽油增程发动机
with a petrol-powered range extender?
那只是一个小发电机
Well, that's just a little generator
在我需要的时候把电池充满
that keeps the battery topped up if I need it.
你是说你不能完全依靠新技术
What you're saying is you can't rely on new technology.
还有你的座椅
And your seats, they're made
是用胡佛袋里的东西做的
from the contents of a Hoover bag.
失业者手里提着捡破烂的口袋叫做“胡佛袋”
-嗬 这话
- Oh, says the man...
这话是一个座椅是
Says the man whose seats are made
用杰基·斯图尔特的破牛仔裤做的人说的
from Jackie Stewart's old trousers,
Jackie Stewart 知名F1赛车手
这又怎样
which they are.
-那可是... -少废话
- It's... - Whatever!
事实是 在办公室里
The fact is, in the office,
我们受够了他们的斗嘴
we decided we'd had enough of them bickering
决定让他们出去进行一场路测
and told them to go out and do a proper road test.
所以我们这么做了
So we did.
我们从伦敦开始
We began in London
进行一场大猩猩想要的
with a real-world test
道路测试
that Clarkson had thought of.
听着船长 我们现在必须看看
Right, James, we must now see
谁能在最短的时间里打开车后门
who can open their back door in the shortest time.
-为啥 -可能会有紧急情况
- Why? - There could be an emergency.
人们会想知道的
People will want to know.
各就各位 预备开始 我的开了
Ready, steady, go! Oh, mine's open.
哦天呐
Oh, dear.
你不会是要先开了前门
Have you got to open your front door
才可以打开 老实说 小翻门
before you open that-- let's be honest-- a flap?
-这才不是翻门  -这就是翻门
- It's not a flap. - It is a flap.
宝马这是在说 在未来
Are BMW saying that, in the future,
孩子们只有三寸宽吗
children will only be three inches wide?
你都在说些啥玩意儿
What are you talking about?
首先 这根本就不是个问题
For a start, it's hardly a hardship,
而且这可是很大的空间
and that's an enormous space.
你想做这个测试
You only wanted to do that test
只是因为你犯了个错 他犯了个错
because you made a mistake. He made a mistake.
我没有 什么错
I didn't. What mistake?
你错了 你本想要一辆三门高尔夫
You did. You wanted a three-door Golf,
但你没填对表
and you didn't fill the form in properly.
我知道的 你都不会打勾勾
I know that. You can't tick boxes.
五门的更好看
Five doors are better-looking.
不 才没有
No, they're not.
没有人会想要一辆五门高尔夫GTI
Nobody ever wanted a five-door Golf GTI.
-这好土 -我们快上路再来谈谈钱
- It's really naff. - We've got to get on and talk about money.
他还想要一辆红色的
He also wanted a red one.
但是那个他也没填对
He didn't fill that bit in properly, either.
这车 加上很多很多的配件
This car, with many, many optional extras,
才三万六千英镑
was £36,000.
但是船长的宝马i3
Whereas James May's BMW i3 was...
好吧 不如让我们来一探究竟
Well... let's find out, shall we?
你的i3多少钱
How much was your i3?
它四万磅
Well, it was £40,000,
但是我从政府那里拿了五千英镑补贴
but I got £5,000 back from the government,
所以实际价格三万五千英镑
so actually it's £35,000,
比你的低 我想
which is less than yours, I think.
你从政府那里拿了
You were given, by the government,
五千英镑纳税人的钱
£5,000 of taxpayers' money
所以你才可以买这车
so you could buy that car?
又不是我定的规则 你又不能不收
I didn't make the rules. You can't turn it down.
这又不像披头士的官佐勋章
It's not like the Beatles' OBE.
太不要脸了
That is obscene!
我是说 船长是个有钱人
I mean, James May is a wealthy man,
但是那公交车司机却为他的车付钱
but that bus driver has bought his car for him.
说好的公平呢
Where's the justice in that?
你在为他的车付钱 你知道吗
You're paying for his car. Do you know that?
你已经付过了
You have paid for it.
只是想让你知道 你给他的车付了钱
Just so you know, you've paid for his car.
你帮船长买车 他谢过你了没
Has James May thanked you for buying his car for him?
杰里米对此有点意见
Jeremy will have an opinion on this,
尽管他买了一个农场 好多年了
despite having bought a farm on which, for many years,
却啥也不种
he was paid to not grow anything.
这里的拥堵费
Congestion charge here.
开到市中心要11.5英镑
It's £11.50 to drive into the centre.
-我可不用 -当然不用
- Not for me, it isn't. -Of course it isn't.
那个出租车司机 他正在帮你付拥堵费吗
The taxi driver, is he paying for your congestion charge?
我想所有人都得付一点
I suppose everybody must pay a little bit.
船长 船长 打家劫舍
* James May, James May Stealing from the rich *
Denis Moore Song (Robin Hood Theme)
船长 船长 巧取豪夺
* James May, James May Stealing from the poor *
他劫富不济贫 劫贫不济富
* He steals from the rich He steals from the poor *
次次如此 贪得无厌
* And once more, wants it all *
骇人听闻
* That's appalling *
差不多就这样
It nearly works.
我已经受够了
I'd had enough of this,
所以我提出了一个新法子来证明
so I came up with a new way of trying to prove
我的车比他的好
my car was better than his.
船长我能问问你 为什么要把我带到伦敦机场来
James, can I just ask, why have you brought me to London Airport?
因为我要证明我的车比你的快
Because I want to prove that my car is faster than yours.
这很可笑 因为我刚刚听到你说
That's funny, because I just heard you say
你的车要比我的快
that your car's faster than mine.
是的 就是这样
Yeah. Yeah, it is.
-167马力 -嗯哼
- 167 horsepower. - Mm-hm.
我的有性能套件 所以有227马力
Mine has the performance pack, so it produces 227.
-真的嘛 -是的
- Does it? - Yes.
这是官方数据对吧
That's the official figure, is it?
是的
Yes, it is.
-来自大众 -是的
- From VW? - Yes.
大众排放造假事件
-而你竟然相信他们 -是的
- And you believe them? - Yes.
好的听着 我知道你的意思
All right, listen, I know what you mean.
0-150加速赛
Drag race: 0-150.
不要
No.
在没有达成一致之后
Having not agreed on that,
我们在终点的设置上
we then failed to agree
也没有达成一致
on where the finishing line should be.
船长想要一个短距离比赛
James wanted a short race...
而我不想
and I didn't.
-妥了吧  -才没有 太短了
- Compromise. - It isn't. That's too short.
-才不短 这刚好 -就是短了
- It's not. It's exactly right. - It is.
但是最终 我们还是准备出发了
But eventually, we were ready to go.
现在 有件事需要记住 观众们
Now, the thing to remember, viewers,
一台电动机
is that an electric motor
可以在几乎零转速下
delivers enormous torque from nothing,
就提供大量的扭矩
from really low down.
所以在短距离里
So over a short distance,
我毫无疑问可以碾压
I should absolutely cream this.
我们开始吧
Here we go.
DCC 正常
DCC-- normal.
DDC：动态底盘控制系统
转向 正常
Steering-- normal.
驾驶模式  环保
Drive-- eco.
赢船长没必要毁了我的车
No point in ruining my own car to win this.
不用着急
No need to rush.
我要赢了 哦耶
I'm winning. Oh, yes!
我还领先着
I'm still winning.
让我们超过它 加油啊小高尔夫
Let's go get him. Come on, Golfy!
不 不
No. No!
很轻快 但是
Quite sprightly, but er...
但没我想的那么轻快
not sprightly enough, methinks.
再见了船长
See you, James.
我让未来在电视上看起来
Bah! I've made the future look rubbish
就像堆垃圾
on the television.
接着 为了让它看上去更糟
And then, to make it look even worse,
我告诉这利益窃取者
I told the benefit scrounger
我们要启程去德文郡
that we were setting off for Devon.
为什么我们要去德文郡
Erm... Why are we going to Devon?
因为我这里有今晚的两张票
Because we have two tickets tonight
去看罗杰·达尔特雷在从Who单飞之后
to see Roger Daltrey out of the Who
在达特缪尔的酒吧里表演
perform at a pub on Dartmoor.
我们难道就不能等到
Couldn't we just wait for him
他来伦敦表演的时候吗
to come and maybe perform in London?
-因为我确信他会来 -才不要
- Because I'm sure he will. - Well, no.
因为这差不多要开三百二十公里
Because it's a 200-mile drive, or thereabouts,
这给了我们一个机会
it'll give us an opportunity
看看我们的车在现实世界里表现如何
to see how our cars work in the real world.
他的意思是这是个机会来让他宣称
What he means is it's an opportunity for him to claim
过去的车是多么出众
that the car of the past is superior.
为了证明不是这样 我需要充满
To prove it wasn't, I needed to top up
在加速赛中损耗的电力
the charge I'd lost by doing the drag race.
好 如果我查卫星导航
Right, if I look at settings on my satnav,
就可以看到充电和加油站在哪里
I can look at where all the charging and petrol stations are.
我甚至还能知道我将在
I can even tell what sort of charging point
哪个充电桩上充电
I am being offered,
不管我有没有对的卡
whether or not I have the right card for it.
很快 我就找到了我正寻找的东西
And soon, we found exactly what I was looking for.
-这就是未来 -换一个
- It's the future. - Another one.
-太丢脸了 -闭嘴
- Oh, that's such a shame. - Oh, shut up!
因为我的电池电力不够我
Because I didn't have enough juice in the batteries
开到下一个充电点
to make the next charge point,
我打开了我的汽油发电机
I had to turn on my petrol generator,
以免电量更少了
which stopped them going even flatter,
并且使用了专业环保驾驶模式
and engaged ECO PRO+ driving mode.
这意味着我只能开90kph
It does mean I have to do 56mph.
这是专业环保模式的最高时速
That's where ECO PRO+ sets the maximum speed,
因为这样你能得到最大的续航里程
because that way you get the maximum range.
但这也意味着我实际上是个货车司机
But it means I'm effectively a lorry driver.
因为我在专业生态模式 我不能开空调
Because I'm in ECO PRO, I don't get any air-conditioning
或者任何温控
or climate control at all,
因为那费电
because that wastes electricity,
所以这车在缓慢行驶
so the car is slowly steaming up.
它现在在警告我 它说
It's now warning me. It says,
"找个充电站 你个白痴"
"Find a charge station, you idiot!"
你到底得缺多少根筋 才会说
How many screws do you have to have loose before you say
"是的 我要买一辆车
"Yes, I'm gonna buy a car,
在电量低的时候
which, when it's running low on power,
只能开到12kph
has to be driven at 8mph,
空调和灯都关着
with the air conditioning off, and the lights off,
暖气也关了 收音机也关了"
and the heater off, and the radio off.
你何必要这样
Why would you do that?
在护送船长
After several lifetimes
开了几个世纪之后
of driving in convoy with James,
我们终于找到
we finally found
一个能用的充电点
a charge point that worked.
就是这样
That's it.
-这就好了 -是的
- It's done? - Yes.
你不用站着盯着它
You don't have to stand and watch it.
这不像汽油 我们可以走开
It's not like petrol. We can go off
喝杯咖啡 吃点面包
and have a cup of coffee, a sticky bun.
-这要花多久 -一个多小时吧
- How long is it gonna take? - An hour or so.
-一个小时 -是的
- An hour? - Yeah.
给它充满 要花多少钱
How much does it cost... to fill it up?
一分都不用
Nothing.
-什么  -这是免费的
- What? - It's free.
-这怎么可能是免费的 -就是免费的
- How could it be free? - It's free.
你必须得有卡 但是这不花钱
You have to get the card, but it doesn't cost...
-办那卡要多少钱  -一分都不用
- How much does the card cost? - Nothing.
你只要在网上填张表
You fill a form in on the Internet,
它就会邮寄过来
and it comes in the post.
所以我还在为你付
So I'm paying for your fuel--
油钱...不对电钱？
well, your electricity-- as well?
可能吧
Probably.
我真是震惊了
I'm just staggered by this.
这太不公正了
This is iniquitous.
在虚度了一会光阴之后
After killing time for a few minutes...
我要试着去赚些钱
I'm just gonna try and win some money
来付船长这些年的暖气费
to pay for James May's heating bill this year,
这无疑让我很不爽
which... will undoubtedly be down to me.
我决定我再也不想等了
...I decided I couldn't be bothered to wait any more,
所以我要用老方法加了油
so I recharged the old-fashioned way
片刻之后 再次上路
and, in moments, was back on the road.
英国电网只供
Britain only produces
实际用电需求105%的电
5% more power than it actually consumes.
现状正是如此 所以如果每个人都买电动车
That's now. So if everybody starts buying electric cars,
发电站会应付不过来
the power stations won't be able to cope.
电力就会中断
There'll be power cuts,
接着就是抢劫和骚乱
and then there will be looting and anarchy.
都是船长干的好事
That's what James is doing.
他让英国跪了
He is bringing Britain to its knees.
好啊
Yes.
这里有些给杰里米的东西
Here's something for Jeremy.
希望他有个CD播放器
Assuming he's got a CD player.
他的高尔夫GTI里
He's probably got a cassette player
可能还有卡带机
in his Golf GTI.
事实上
Actually,
船长大错特错
May couldn't have been more wrong.
这车可能来自过去 但是瞧瞧这个
This car may be from the past, but check this out.
它正在加速 你可能听到了
It's accelerating now, you can probably hear that,
但是我可并没有干这个
but I'm not doing it.
我的前视雷达
The radar in front of me
正在帮我与前车
is maintaining a safe distance
保持一个安全距离
behind the car in front.
他快我就快
He goes faster, I go faster.
他慢我也慢
He slows down, I slow down.
有车现在变到中间车道
Car pulling out now into the middle lane.
这车能检测到
The car will sense that.
是的 它现在正让我退到
Yeah. It's now dropping me
那辆车的后面
back from that.
我甚至都不用转向
I don't even have to steer,
因为它会自己保持在白线内
because it'll keep itself between the white lines.
看
Look.
谷歌一直在大惊小怪
Google is making a big fuss.
"看我们有多聪明
"Ooh, aren't we clever?
我们在造能自动行驶的车"
We're making a self-driving car."
已经有了 我开的就是
It's already here! I'm driving it.
它来自1978年
And it's from 1978.
在充了一个小时之后
After an hour's charging,
我又继续上路
I was back on the move.
我倒是觉得在高速公路上的服务站
I actually think the service station on the motorway
应该为电动车车主专设一区
should have an electric-car driver section,
在那里 你懂得
where there are, you know,
得有十分复杂的拼图游戏和大富翁
very complicated jigsaw puzzles and a Monopoly set,
或者一些填色图画
or maybe some painting-by-numbers.
未填色的画作线稿，空白处有数字，可以按照编号填充颜色
还有270公里
It is 170 miles to go.
天哪看看 一直要开到那里
God, look at it. It's all the way down there.
在很前方
Many miles ahead,
我正忙着开启
I was busy firing up
GTI的苹果CarPlay系统
the GTI's Apple CarPlay system.
我现在正打算给船长发个信息
Right, I'm gonna send James May a text message now,
在很多车里这都是违法的
which would be illegal in most cars,
但在这车里可不是
but not in this one.
请问你想给谁发送消息
To whom should I send your message?
梅
May.
您在说什么 啊哦 出了些问题
What was that again? Uh-oh, something's wrong.
请您再试一次
Can you try again?
把这段切了
Edit that out.
我应该发送给谁
To whom shall I send it?
梅
May.
我不知道你说"巴里"的意思
I don't know what you mean by "Barry".
-我应该发送给谁 -我没说"巴里"
- To whom shall I send it? - I didn't say "Barry".
梅
May.
这可不行啊 大众 得了吧
This is not doing well, Volkswagen. Come on.
好的 您想对梅说什么
OK. What do you want to say to May?
"梅 你这个十足的白痴"
"May, you're a blithering idiot,
你那蠢车毁了我的一天
and your stupid car is ruining my day."
您发送给梅的消息如下
Your message to May says,
"你的兄弟是白痴 还有你那蠢车已经准备好了"
"Your brother is idiot and your stupid car is ready."
准备好发送了吗
Ready to send it?
"你的兄弟是白痴"
"Your brother is idiot"?
啥 他从来我见过我兄弟
What? He's never met my brother.
他怎么知道他是白痴
How does he know he's an idiot?
因为我下了高速
Because I'd turned off the motorway
选了更能直达达特穆尔的路线
to take the more direct route to Dartmoor,
我觉得最好通知船长一声
I thought I'd better let James know that as well.
我打算走A34和A303公路
Erm... I'm going on the A34 and the A303.
在那里等你
I'll see you there.
您给梅的消息写道
Your message to May says,
"我要去三个RC的第一层"
"I'm going on the first floor of the three RC."
准备发送吗
Ready to send it?
与此同时 我选了更长的高速公路路线
I, meanwhile, was using the longer motorway route
因为这里有更多的充电站
because there'd be more charging points.
于是我踩下了油门
But I had my foot down.
现在 象征未来的电动车
And now... the electric car of the future
正在超一台保时捷911 Turbo S
is overtaking a Porsche 911 Turbo S.
瞧好了
There we go.
我开着一辆车在高速公路上
I'm driving along in a car on the motorway
以标准限速
at motorway speeds,
超过了所有人
overtaking everybody.
哦不 自从我加满油以后
Oh, no. Since I filled up,
我已经用了八分之一了
I've used... an eighth of a tank.
哦不
Oh, no!
自从我深入德文郡的郊区
And soon I was deep in the Devon countryside,
这优秀的高速巡航利器
where my excellent motorway cruising machine
变成了一辆真正的GTI
had become a GTI.
现在我们在运动模式了
We're in full sport mode now.
它有个令人惊讶的前差速器
It's got an astonishing front differential,
所以你可以大力地将车驶入每个弯道
so you can hurl the car into any corner
以任何你能想到的速度
at any speed that takes your fancy,
而且知道你可以成功的出弯
knowing you're gonna come out on the other side OK.
我没开玩笑 在这样的路上
I'm not kidding. On a road like this
湿叶和泥巴到处都是
with wet leaves and mud everywhere,
这车可以和任何法拉利一样快
this car is as fast as any Ferrari.
它就是如此
It just is.
在接下来的很长一段时间里
Many hours from now,
船长会像这样一直念叨着
James May's going to be coming along here saying,
"我还有13%的电量和2%的油"
"Right, I've got 13% battery and 2% fuel,
所以如果我油耗百公里17升 可以..."
so if I do 13.8 miles to the gallon, I should..."
明明可以做松油门甩尾
Who wants to do maths
为什么还要做算数
when they could do lift-off oversteer?
在i3 多亏了我娴熟的驾驶技术
In the i3, thanks to my exuberant driving,
我确实得做些算数
I was indeed having to do some maths.
能源管理更新
Energy management update:
如果我继续这么开
I have 36 miles of electric power remaining,
电力还可以开58公里
if I'm driving like this,
还有55公里的汽油剩余
and 34 miles of petrol range left.
所以我得在这些服务区停车
So I'm going to stop at these services
再填满那小油箱
and I'm going to fill up the little fuel tank.
9英镑 这实在是
Nine quid. That is absolutely...
其实我加多了
I've overfilled it, in fact.
如果你开一辆GTI
If you drive a GTI,
你会更快地到你想去的地方
you're going to get to where you're going more quickly,
这就意味着你会见到更多的人
which means you're going to meet more people,
有更多的阅历 学到更多的东西
have more experiences, learn more stuff.
速度让你聪明
Speed makes you cleverer.
同理 如果你开一辆宝马i3
Whereas, if you drive a BMW i3,
你去哪里都得迟
you're gonna get everywhere late.
你会错过很多事
You're gonna miss out on things.
你会错过戏剧 文化 诗歌
You'll miss out on theatre, culture, poetry.
还有爱
Love.
你会徒有人类空荡的躯壳
You'll be a hollowed-out husk of a man.
"连接你的车辆并确认"
"Connect your vehicle and validate."
"确认"是什么意思 我已经确认了啊
What do they mean, "validate"? I've already validated.
到了 我的探索结束了
And here we are. My quest is at an end.
在对的时间 万事皆佳
I'm in good time. All is well.
而且我还受到了款待
And I was in for a treat,
因为和罗杰·达尔特雷同台的是
because joining Roger Daltrey on stage
传奇的吉他手威尔科·约翰逊
was legendary guitarist Wilko Johnson.
那个传说中的威尔科·约翰逊
The fabulous Wilko Johnson!
"站点正在等待来自车辆的充电请求
"Station waiting for a charge request from the vehicle.
初始化 充电中"
Initialisation. Charging."
这没在充电
It's not charging.
*等一下 宝贝*
* Well, wait a minute, baby *
*你要干什么*
* Well, whatcha gonna do? *
观众们 我们现在所处的状况是
OK, viewers, here is where we're at.
最后一个充电站不管用
That last charging station wasn't working.
电量还剩下90公里
We have about 60 miles to go.
所以答案是
So the answer is...
环保模式驾驶
eco driving.
*我漂浮在街道之上*
* Then I float on Down the street *
*脸上挂着的笑容*
* Smiling at the faces
*我所见如是*
* That I meet *
我不能切换到快速模式
I'm not switching it into fast mode.
这太浪费了
It's too wasteful.
*然后我回到了家*
* Then I'm going back home *
离酒吧还有29公里
It is 18 miles to the pub.
我还剩下26公里的电力
I have 16 miles of electric left.
还有什么东西可以关掉吗
Is there anything else I can turn off?
最终 经过了很多里程的焦虑之后
Finally, after much range anxiety...
罗杰·达尔特雷 我来了
Roger Daltrey, here I come!
我做到了
...I made it.
谢谢你们的到来 晚安
Thanks for coming, and good night!
卧槽
Oh, cock!
所以等等
- So... Hang on.
-你的车是未来 -是的
- Your car of the future... - Yes?
两个充电站
Two of the charging points
在你这简单的旅程里 两个坏了
you went to on that simple journey, two were broken?
是的 这很不寻常 但重点是
Yes, that is very unusual. But the point is,
如果我可以
if I'd been allowed to set off
以满电满油的状态开始
with a full electric charge and a full little fuel tank,
我可以到终点 公认地开90kph
I could have got there-- admittedly a lot at 56mph--
而且我只用停下来一次
but I would have done it with one stop.
90kph 未来听起来真无趣 船长
56mph. The future does sound boring, James.
而且你还会错过演出
And you still would have missed the gig.
那片子过时了
That film is out of date.
你再也不会从政府那里拿到五千英镑了
You don't get £5,000 from the government any more.
-你只会拿到四千五百英镑 -人们该如何应对啊
- You only get £4,500. - How will people cope?
我觉得我们所做的证明了
I think what we've done there is prove
他的车现在还不值得买
his car is not really worth buying just yet.
-别争了 就不是 它还没完善 -别又开始了
- Don't argue. It isn't. It's not quite finished. - Don't start again.
在我们继续之前 我还要再说一点
Before we move on, I want to tell you a little bit more
关于大众的短信系统
about that Volkswagen system of texting.
因为有天我在车里试着发短信
Cos I was using that to send a text from my car
给我的小女儿
the other day to my youngest daughter,
我在结尾打了四个亲亲 这很正常
and I put four kisses at the end, which is normal.
我说"X-X-X-X" 而这是她收到的
And I said "X-X-X-X", OK? This is what she got.
哦不
- Oh, no!
这就尴尬了
Oh, that is awkward!
她回复了什么
What did she say?
- 简直尴尬  - 你试试连着说几个X
- Oh, that is awkward. - Say it, "X-X-X-X".
就是这个结果
That's what comes out.
她从自己爹那收到这样的信息
What sort of face did she pull
是个什么表情
when she got that from her dad?
想吐
Vomitous. Vomitous.
我们再没联系过
We haven't spoken since.
卡娅 对不起 是车的问题
Katya, I'm sorry. It was the car!
-继续节目  -好主意
- Move on! - Yes, let's move on.
是时候参观一下聊天公司的总部
It is now time for us to visit the headquarters of Chat & Co,
当然 其总部位于唠嗑街
who are, of course, based on Conversation Street.
最好的一期 好的 首先
Best one yet. Anyway, we begin...
首先来说说迪拜
We begin with Dubai, in fact.
第一次我去那的时候
Cos the first time I came here, which was...
也就20年前 那还是个小村庄
was only 20 years ago, it was like a small village.
找不到比我更高的东西了
I was the tallest thing in it.
是吗
Were you?
现在看这 不可思议
Now look at it. It's unbelievable!
- 现在可不一样了  - 难以置信
- It's not that now, is it? - It is unbelievable, that.
你们知道吗 我身上这件衬衫
Do you know, this shirt is older
比你们从窗外看到的一切更老
than everything you can see out of that window.
詹姆斯 那衬衫比迦太基古城还老 简直不忍直视
James, that shirt is older than Carthage, mate. Look at it.
迦太基：腓尼基人建立的古国
是有一点
It is getting on a bit.
重点在于
Anyway, the point I'm trying to make is,
我几年前第一次来时
a few years ago, when I first came here,
这里没有任何交通法规
there were virtually no motoring laws at all.
有天早上我在旅馆醒来时
I woke up one morning in my hotel--
也是当时唯一的旅馆
the hotel, there was only one--
我在那旅馆里回想
in the hotel, thinking,
昨晚我怎么回来的
"How did I get back here last night?"
向窗外看去 两道轮印
Looked out of the window, two wheel marks
径直穿过景观环岛
right over the ornamental roundabout.
而我的揽胜停在了花圃里
And in the flowerbed, my Range Rover.
杰里米 你停车时是有多累
Jeremy, were you very tired when you parked it?
-眼睛都睁不开了  -好吧
- I was off my face with tiredness. - OK. OK.
-行  -很难保持清醒
- OK. - Barely able to concentrate.
当时真的很随便
But it was an extraordinary free-for-all,
当然现在不一样了
which I bet it isn't now.
现在已经全然不同了
It really isn't now.
现在有很多的规则
There are now very many rules
以及严厉的惩罚 我这有几条
and many stiff punishments. I've got some of them here.
拖欠汽车贷款
Getting behind on the repayments on your car loan,
会进监狱
you go to prison.
向其他司机比出粗鲁手势 进监狱
Making rude gestures at other motorists, you go to prison.
我17岁时
They're all just the things I did
这些事全干过了
when I was 17 every day.
我很赞同
I quite approve of that.
我刚在想 在英国
I'm just thinking of all the things
如果严格执行的话 哪些行为
that you could be sent to prison for in Britain
应该被送进监狱
if we ran it properly.
这个话题不错 我想到了
A very good conversation, isn't it? Here's one.
那些从加完油上车
Anyone who takes more than five seconds
到开车走人 花费时间
between getting in their car after filling up with petrol
超过5秒的人
and driving off.
很有道理
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
没错
Definitely.
你懂我的意思吧
Do you know what I mean by--
-没错  -在磨蹭啥呢
- Definitely. - What do they do?
-我又想到一个  -什么
- I know. - What?
用一片木头装菜的
Restaurant owners who serve food
餐厅老板
on a piece of wood.
这和车无关吧
Erm, It's not very car-related,
-不是吗  -是无关 但是
- is it, really? - No, it's not, but--
赫斯顿 布卢门撒尔就这么干的
Heston Blumenthal does that.
赫斯顿 布卢门撒尔：英国厨师 擅长分子美食 开有同名米其林星级餐厅
没错 他就这么干
Yes, he does. Exactly.
如果赫斯顿你在看节目 小心进监狱哦
Heston, if you're watching... prison.
蹲号子哦
You, prison.
我超讨厌用一片木头盛菜
I hate that-- food on a piece of wood.
告诉你我讨厌什么
I tell you what I hate.
我可能之前提过几次
I may have mentioned this a couple of times before.
我认为这行为应该判监禁
And I think it should be imprisonable.
任何允许机舱温度高于20℃的
Any pilot who allows the cabin of the plane
飞机机长
to be more than 68°F.
-天 又来了  -这点我同意
- Oh, God. Here we go. - I'm with you on that.
-现在所有飞机都太热了  -没错
- All planes are too hot these days. - They are.
这只是你的例行吐槽
It's just a standard moan of yours.
-我知道  -天啊
- I know. I know. - Oh, God.
我们确实经常一起坐飞机
We do have to fly together, but I make every effort
每次长途飞行 我都尽量不和大猩猩一起坐
not to sit near Jeremy Clarkson for a long flight.
但每次
But eventually, you know,
灯一关 眼前一黑
they turn the lights off and it goes all dark,
10分钟后 黑暗中会响起这个声音
and after ten minutes this voice over in the blackness goes,
"还有比这更热的飞机吗"
"It's literally the hottest place in the world!"
-真的很热  -"我们是要飞向太阳吗
- It is. - "Are we flying into the sun?
温度再高一点 我就要开窗户了"
If it gets any hotter, I shall open a window!"
我听过无数遍了
I've heard all of this so many times.
讲真 他们为什么要这样
Honestly, why do they do it?
为什么 这里有飞行员吗
Why? Are there any pilots here?
-这  -你是飞行员吗
- Yeah. - You are a pilot?
你为什么把温度调那么高
Why do you do it?
你为什么要蒸我们 你哪家公司的
Why do you boil us all? Who do you fly with?
-阿提哈德航空公司  -阿提哈德
- Etihad. - Etihad.
-你飞机上温度高吗  -很高
- How hot are the planes? - Very warm.
新规矩
Well, there's a new rule.
我现在警告你
I'm telling you. I'm warning you.
我很严肃的警告你
I'm seriously warning you on this one.
如果机舱温度高于20℃ 你一落地
You land. If it's gone over 68 in the cabin,
直接判刑50年
straight to prison for 50 years.
我能说一句吗 既然你在这里
Can I also say, since you're in here--
-我们有点跑题了 -这值得指出
- We've gone off topic. - It's worth pointing this out.
既然你在这里 当我们都打算睡觉的时候
Since you're in here, when we're trying to sleep,
别告诉我们外面的温度是
don't tell us the outside temperature
零下57度
is 57 below zero,
因为我们根本不在乎
cos we don't give a toss.
反正你也不能开窗
Cos you can't open the window anyway.
我们在乎飞机里的温度
We care about the temperature in the plane.
只是一些规矩而已
Just a few rules.
总之 让我们继续
Anyway, let's move it on.
我们能说回到车上吗
Shall we get back on to some cars?
是的 旅行
Yeah, travel--
恩 和旅行有关的事情
Well, sort of travel-related stuff. OK.
我这里有张照片
I've got a photograph here
是英国关于
of Britain's idea
基础设施建设的点子
of infrastructure investment, OK?
这在剑桥 这是...
This is in Cambridge. It's erm...
这是他们设计的T字路口
It's a T-junction that they've designed,
也只有他们自己知道
for reasons known only to themselves,
为什么它这么像环岛
to look like a roundabout.
让我猜猜看
Yeah, and let me guess.
这花了一百万吧
It cost 100 grand to do it?
不 这花了五十万英镑
No, it was £500,000.
-当然 -五十万英镑
- Of course it was, yeah. - Half a million pounds
他们用纳税人的钱就做这个
they charged the taxpayer for that.
-就用一些瓷砖 -正是
- For some paving slabs. - Exactly.
不管怎样 在迪拜所谓的基础设施
Anyway, Dubai's idea of infrastructure investment
就有点不一样了
is a little bit different,
因为他们在计划这个
cos what they're planning is this.
这叫超级高铁
It's called the Hyper Loop.
它有点像铁道列车
It's like a tube train.
它将从迪拜开往阿布扎比
And it'll go from Dubai to Abu Dhabi,
差不多有160公里
which is about 100 miles away,
-只需12分钟 -12分钟
- in 12 minutes. - 12 minutes!
12分钟 这就是所需要的时间
12 minutes. That's how long that will take.
它有多快
So how fast does it go?
每小时800公里
500 miles an hour.
这实在是太惊人了 真的
I mean, that is just breath-taking. It really is.
-你刚刚是说有160公里吗 -是的
- Did you say it was 100 miles? - Yeah.
它能以800公里的时速在12分钟内走160公里
It's going 100 miles at 500mph in 12 minutes.
这意味着它可以瞬间加速至800kph
That means it accelerates to 500mph instantly.
-嗯 -在里面推辆饮料小推车
- Mm. - You're gonna have trouble
你会出事的
holding on to the drinks trolley in that.
当它启动的时候 你会拉裤子
When it sets off, you'll poo yourself.
然后当它停下来
Then, when it stops,
你又会尿自己一身
you'll wee yourself at the end.
这里 这里有医生吗
It's a... Are there any doctors here?
我只是说说 这可不是什么医疗纠纷
I'm just saying. It's not a medical argument.
-我只是说说 -我不确定你对不对
- I'm just saying. - I'm not sure you're right.
好吧 想想牛顿
Well, think about Newton.
当它起步加速时 你会拉裤子
If you set off, you'll poo yourself, yes,
但是当它减速的时候 你会反向拉裤子
but when it slows down, you'll un-poo yourself,
因为万物都会受到等大的反向作用力
because everything has an equal and opposite reaction.
我说的没错吧 这里有物理学家吗
I'm roughly right, aren't I? Any physicists here?
-我觉得我们该继续了 -是的
- I think we should move on. - Yeah.
在这一季开头
Right at the beginning of the series,
哈蒙德和我提出了
Richard Hammond and I came up
一个绝妙的主意叫做
with a rather brilliant idea called...
让船长
...Making James May
做他不想做的事情
Do Things He Doesn't Want To Do.
是的 偶然情况下的好点子
Yep. A brilliant idea for an occasional feature.
我们让他去南非参加了一个甜甜圈节
We made him go to a doughnuting festival in South Africa.
-是的 -他很讨厌这个
- Yeah. - He hated it.
然后他觉得我们把这忘了
Then he thought we'd forgotten about it.
但是我们并没有
But we hadn't.
这里就是那种
This is the sort of countryside
人们可以享受美好事物的郊外
where people can do nice things,
比如散散步或者野餐
like go for a walk or a picnic.
然而这里 是那种
This, however, is the sort of countryside
会成为我今天归属的郊外—泥巴
that will be my home for the day-- mud.
是的 我喜欢泥巴
Yes, I love mud.
当我说我爱泥巴的时候 其实在说我恨它
When I say I love mud, I mean I hate mud.
但是今天 跟我一起的人都喜欢
But the people with me here today really do love it.
他们梦寐以求
They dream of the stuff.
在我身后的这些人叫做绞盘党
These people behind me are called winchers,
他们喜欢做的事情就是拉绞盘
and what they like doing is winching.
他们会故意
They will drive, deliberately,
开进像那里的泥坑
into something like that puddle over there...
直到陷进去 然后再用绞盘拉出来
..until they get stuck, and then winch themselves out.
做完以后 他们会找另一处
When they've done that, they'll find another one...
像这样循环往复
and do it again, and again,
折腾一整天
and again, and again, all day long.
绞盘党们看起来痴迷于
Winchers seem to be obsessed
让日子尽可能的艰难
with making life as difficult as possible.
他们将定向越野标记点
They put orienteering punches
放在几乎不可能的位置
in almost unreachable locations...
然后试图把他们的4x4s开到那里
and then try to get their 4x4s right up to them,
谢默斯道尔 我今天的绞盘兄弟解释道
as Seamus Doyle, my winch buddy for the day, explained.
有50个标记点
There are 50 punches
遍布这个场所的不同地方
dotted around in different parts of the site.
在车边有一张打孔卡
We have a punch card on the side of the vehicle.
你要用它够到标记点
You've got to get this punchcard to the punch.
这些标记点会拴在绳子上
The punch will be on a string
有可能离树两尺远 或者一尺
maybe 2ft long from the tree, or maybe 1ft.
所以你就可以在数字上打卡
So you've got to punch the number.
-就像打孔机 -是的
- Like a hole puncher? - Yes.
当你卡住的时候
When you get stuck,
因为你会卡主
because you're gonna get stuck...
-是的 -我得逃出来
- Yes. Yeah, yeah. - I have to get out
然后把绞盘挂在树上
and attach the winch to a tree?
是的 你得出来
Yes, you'll get out,
你得带着你的皮带
and you'll get your strap with you.
用皮带包着可以保护树
The strap goes round the tree to protect the tree.
然后你再把你的绞盘挂在树上
Then you bring your wincher up to the tree,
或者随便什么东西
or whatever obstacle we attach it to,
我会操作那些按钮
and I'll operate the buttons.
-你的英语很好  -谢谢
- Your English is excellent. - Thank you.
我练习了很久了
I've been practising for a long time now.
在上面花了很多力气
A lot of practice has gone into that.
比赛一开始
As soon as the contest began,
谢默斯指明了 我人生中的新角色
Seamus made it plain that my new role in life
就是做他的绞盘婊
was to be his winch bitch.
走啊 走走走
OK, got to go, go, go.
-什么 我要走出去 -是的
- What, I've got to get out? - Yeah.
你觉得我还可以往哪走
Where the hell do you think I'm gonna go?
拿着绞车缆索到那棵树那里
Go with the winch rope to that tree over there.
哦伙计啊
Oh, man!
这感觉有点像...
This is like being a...
他妈的河马
(BLEEP) hippopotamus.
时间紧迫
OK, the clock is ticking.
在拿到了我们第一个标记点之后
Having got our first punch,
我希望今天能过得稍微好一点
I was hoping the day might get a bit less terrible.
但是并没有
But it didn't.
-哦天 -詹姆斯 给力啊
- Oh, man! - James, come on, will you?
我在绞我自己
I'm winching myself.
这样好多了
Oh, that's much better.
好吧 我说这"好多了"
Well, I say it's "much better",
其实是少点操蛋
it's less shit.
走 我们要弥补时间
Go! We've got to make up time.
-我有个好点子 -什么
- I've got a great idea. - Yes?
-为什么不是你出来打卡 -不要
- Why don't you get out and get the punch? - No.
为什么我一直要干这个
Why do I have to keep doing it?
我要做司机 那样行不通
Me being the driver, it doesn't work that way.
好吧 我们接下来去哪儿郊游啊
Right, where next on our lovely Sunday drive?
-我们要下去 -别傻了
- We're going down here. - Don't be stupid.
-我们又卡住了
- We're stuck again.
出去绞起来 伙计
Get the winch out here, buddy.
看到那里的树了吗
See the tree over there?
这个全他妈的是树
The place is full of (BLEEP) trees.
太糟糕了
This is terrible.
我的神啊
Christ!
在一些偶然的情况下
On the odd occasion when I did manage
我即使能坐在车里
a sit-down in the car,
谢默斯也要添乱
Seamus even managed to ruin that.
这压根没必要
That wasn't even necessary.
你只是想惹怒我
You just did that to piss me off.
不不不
No, no, no.
我们快做到了 船长
We nearly made it, James.
是的 但是你没做到 我可以回家了吗
Yeah, but you didn't. Now can I go home?
在那个山丘上打地锚
Ground anchor over the hill.
-你就坐那儿对吧 -我不走 放心
- You just sit there, OK? - I'll be here, OK, yeah.
我们在这里四个小时了
It's four hours we've been in here now,
然而我们实际的行进距离...
and we've travelled, in reality...
只有150米
...150 metres.
今天要是能做任何其他事
All the things I could be doing today
我都愿意做
that I would rather do,
包括自残
which include self-harm.
不幸中的万幸 比赛总算要结束了
Mercifully, the contest eventually came to an end,
我们也终于回程参加颁奖礼
and we were finally on our way back to prize-giving.
-好消息是我们不是最后一名 -你怎么知道的
- The good news is we're not gonna come last. - How do you know?
因为十点的时候有个男孩车坏了
Because one of the boys broke down since ten o'clock.
他真他妈走运
Lucky bastard.
哦天呐
Oh, geez!
我上去了上去了
I'm on it. I'm on it.
不 你过头了
No, you're gonna overdo it!
不 这可以的 没事的
-No, it's OK. You're OK.
-你个白痴 -都怪你
-You idiot! - Your fault!
是你在开车 傻子
It was you driving, you fool!
这下面好臭
It stinks down here.
神呐 这是什么玩意儿
God! What is this stuff?
英国大陆
England.
最终 我们还是赶上了颁奖
At last, we made it back for the prize-giving.
所以 快速总结一下
So, here's a quick sum-up.
在经历了7个小时之后
Er... At the end of a seven-hour day,
我被卡了50余次
I've... been stuck 50-something times.
我摔了有
Erm... I've fallen over,
我也没数 差不多25次
I haven't actually been counting, something like 25 times.
我差点在三个泥坑里淹死
I've nearly drowned in three puddles.
如果我可以赢一个绞盘或者绞盘套
And that wouldn't be so bad
可能还不算太糟
if I was gonna win a winch or a winch cover
或者赢一卷新绳之类的
or a new piece of rope or something like that,
但是 事实截然相反
but, in fact, in the rollover,
我们的打孔卡掉下来了 从严格意义上说
we tore the punchcard off, which means, technically,
我们得从头开始比赛
we've got to start again from the beginning.
但是我宁可把去把自己淹死
But I've decided to go and drown myself instead.
-我很喜欢谢默斯 -是的 我喜欢他
- I like Seamus a lot. - Yeah, I like him.
-谢默斯是我新的好朋友 -这当然啦
- Seamus is my new best friend. - Yeah, definitely.
-毁了船长 -我们还要来更多这样的
- Ruined James May. - We need to do a lot more of those.
-是的 更多 -非常多
- Yeah, a lot more. A lot more. - Many more.
所以 船长 有任何你喜欢的地方吗
So, James, was there any aspect of that that you liked?
-没有 -很好
- No. - Good.
继续 现在是时候
So, moving on, it's time now
进入明星脑碰脑
to play Celebrity Brain Crash.
-这丝毫没有进步 -是没有
- That doesn't get any better. - It doesn't!
总之 我们今天的嘉宾
Anyway, our guest today
是一级方程式赛车里闪亮的新星
is a shining star from the world of Formula One.
他也是一个很有勇气的年轻人
He's also a very brave young man,
因为 即使他充分了解到
because, even though he is fully aware
之前发生在
of all of the calamities
其他名人身上 在试图来帐篷时
that have befallen all the other celebrities
发生的惨案
that have tried to come to our tent,
他还是选择坐气垫船来
he's elected to arrive in a hovercraft.
女士们先生们 丹尼尔·里卡多
Ladies and gentlemen, Daniel Ricciardo!
-他来了 -他来了
-And there he is. -There he is.
戴上他的头盔
Putting his helmet on.
我觉得 这是明智的举动
That's a wise move, I think. A wise move.
我真的真的很喜欢丹尼尔·里卡多
I genuinely, genuinely like Daniel Ricciardo,
因为他真的是一个很好的人
because he is a truly nice man.
他是个好人
He's a truly nice man,
他还非常开心和愉快
and he's also extremely happy and cheerful.
只是 以我的个人经验
I just... Well, I know from personal experience,
气垫船很难控制
hovercrafts are tricky to control.
杰里米 他可是一个F1车手
Yeah, Jeremy, he's a Formula One driver.
-他能做到的 -可是风很大
- He's got this covered. - No, but it's windy.
哦他来了 他来了 到了
Oh, here he comes. Here he is, arriving now.
-他做的很好 -操控得很好
- He's fine with that. - Wrestling with the controls and doing well.
-是的 -噢他开过了
- Yeah. - Oh, he's overshot.
他是有点开过了 哦天哪
He's overshot a bit there. Oh, dear.
哦不
Oh, no!
哦那就是说...他来不了了
Oh, there's been... No, there's been a... No.
我去 他卷到风扇里了 风扇啊
Oh, God! He's going in the fan! He's going in the fan!
哦不
Oh, no!
这...
Oh, that...
看那头盔
The helmet...
还好头盔和他的头一起卡住了马达
The helmet has now thankfully jammed the motor with his head.
是的 太迟了
Yeah, it's too late.
所以是不是说 他来不了了
Does that mean he's not coming on, then?
听着船长 他被榨了汁 而且布满窗户
Well, James, he's been liquidised and now he's all over the window,
所以他来不了了
so, no, he's not.
与其说在帐篷里 不如说在帐篷上
Yeah, he's not in the tent so much as on it.
是的...
Yeah. Uh...
-我们接下来干嘛 -总得做点什么
- What do we do next? - We've got to do something.
好吧 你不介意的话 我去把它擦干净
Well, I'm gonna clean that off, if you don't mind.
太让人分心了 还很恶心
It is distracting and off-putting.
我们怎么打发时间
How do we fill the time?
没事 我早就预见到
It's all right, because I thought
会发生这种事
something like this might happen.
所以我们抵达之后
So when we arrived last night,
我出门拍了一小段视频
I went out and I made a little film.
谢天谢地 什么视频
Thank God for that. What was it?
-好的 让我们... -我们把它遮起来
- Well, let's just... - We'll cover this up.
我想告诉你们
I'd like to talk to you now--
-不 我们得拉近镜头 -好主意
- No, we need to tighten the shot. - Good idea.
镜头对准他 就拍脸
Tighten it on him. Just our faces.
注意力集中在我
Concentrate on me and what I'm saying,
还有我说的话上
and not on anything else
不要看其他的东西
that you might be tempted to look at.
好的 保时捷918
Erm... Now, the Porsche 918,
之前的节目中我们证明了
earlier in this series of programmes we saw it in action
它是三大神车中
and proved that it is the ultimate
最后的王者
of the hypercar Holy Trinity
我们拿它和法拉利 迈凯伦做对比
when we put it against the Ferrari and the McLaren.
但我总是想
But I've always wondered,
"如果我们跑直线的话
"How would it fare in a straight race
它和布加迪威龙谁快"
against a Bugatti Veyron?"
现在我们在超级跑车之乡
And as we are in the home of the hypercar,
应该在这儿一探究竟
this is the place to find out.
好 对准我 怎么样 好的
Yeah. Now, tight on me. Are we tight? Good. Erm...
这是...
This is, then...
这是一场竞速
This is a... It's a race
过去和未来之间的对决
between the future and the past.
今晚的第二次了
Second time this evening.
是的 和你的片子很像
Yeah, much like your film,
但这次是激动人心的
only this one is exciting.
好的 终于
So, here we are.
昔日的性能王者
The grand old man of performance
再次出山 捍卫正名
coming out one more time to defend his title
和后起之秀同台竞技
against one of the young upstarts.
纸面数据如下
Here's how it all pans out on paper.
布加迪威龙:百公里加速2.5秒
Bugatti Veyron: 0-60, 2.5 seconds.
功率质量比:
Power-to-weight ratio:
每吨523马力
523 brake horsepower per tonne.
保时捷918:百公里加速2.6秒
The 918: 0-60, 2.6 seconds,
但是功率质量比为
but a power-to-weight ratio
每吨535马力
of 535 brake horsepower per tonne.
然而 在第一期节目中
However, as we learned when we raced the 918
我们驾驶918对抗拉法和P1
against the LaFerrari and the P1 in our first show,
这种指标完全没用
hard facts like that count for nothing.
最终看的还是这个
In the end, it's all down to this.
我准备好比赛了
And I'm ready to race.
其实...
Actually...
爽
Yeah.
最后一点死皮
Last bit of dead skin.
好的 弹射起步:赛道模式
OK. Launch control: race mode.
这儿代表着未来
Representing the future here.
我想...只要我保持领先
I think... if I can just stay ahead...
太接近了
This is going to be so close!
未来要获胜了
The future is gonna take it!
抱歉 威龙 但是你的皇冠不再
So sorry, Veyron, but your crown is gone.
哇喔
Wow!
多好的车啊
What a device this is.
显然 我打算就这么收尾了
I was gonna call it a day at that, obviously,
但这儿有个家伙想拿日产比一比
but there's a bloke here wants to race his Nissan.
实在是有点丢人
It's a bit embarrassing, really,
但你总不能惹毛当地人
but you don't want to upset the locals.
所以比赛吧 我们走
So, OK, race is on. Here we go.
我们速战速决
Let's get this over with.
跑比赛 说抱歉 然后过
Do race, apologise, move on.
什么
What?
他居然用日产途乐甩开我了
He's pulling away in a Nissan Patrol!
到底 发生了 什么
What... just... happened?
等一下
So, hang on a minute.
在这一季的开头
At the beginning of this series,
我们把那三辆超跑神车
we bigged up the hypercar Holy Trinity
吹成了有史以来
as the three greatest cars
构思和发明过的最好的车
ever to have been conceived and invented.
-是的 -而它们之中最快的...
- Yeah. - And the fastest of all of them...
-嗯 -...被一辆日产面包车吊打
- Yes. - ...was beaten by a Datsun van.
是的
Yes. Yes.
它用的什么鬼引擎
What the hell engine did it have?
事实上它有1900匹马力
Well, it turns out it's got 1,900 horsepower.
-保时捷想什么呢 -就是说
- What were Porsche thinking of? - I know.
回炉重造吧 伙计们
Back to the drawing boards, lads,
-我们先遮着点 -很好
- and we'll gloss over that. - Exactly right.
你太丢人了 保时捷
Your embarrassing mistake, Porsche.
现在 我想坦白说 实际上
Now, I'd like to make a confession, actually, and it's this.
我一直不会真正的漂移
I've never been able to drift properly.
这实在是....别管他
It's just... I know, just ignore him.
没什么好看的
Nothing to see. Nothing to see.
这儿没东西可看
Nothing to see here.
只是一个男人在做他的工作
It's just a man doing his job.
我一直不会正确地漂移
I've never been able to drift properly.
我能引发车的侧滑
I can provoke a car, you know, into a slide,
但是我没法控制住
but I couldn't hold it there.
总是原地打转 或者撞车
It would always just spin off and crash.
正是 我想说
No, exactly. I mean,
你们以前看到他做的漂移
everything you've ever seen in the past of him drifting
都是使用烟雾 镜子 神剪辑
has been done with smoke, mirrors, clever editing
老实说 还有特技车手
and, let's be honest, stunt drivers.
所以当我们开始录制Grand Tour的时候
So I decided when we started making Grand Tour
我决定改变这一现状
that I had to go out and change that,
并学会如何正确地漂移
and learn how to do it properly.
有一种选项
One option would be to go
就是周六晚上去超市的停车场
to a supermarket car park on a Saturday night,
但我来到了法国
but instead I came here to France.
准确地说 到了高度机密的
Specifically, to the top-secret
闲杂人等
禁止入内
拉度测试中心
Ladoux test centre,
米其林在这里研发轮胎
where Michelin develops its tyres.
我来这里有几个原因
There are several reasons why I'm here.
首先 他们有场地
First, they have the space.
43公里的测试跑道和定圆漂移场
Twenty-seven miles of test tracks and skid pans.
其次 如果你想了解漂移
Second, if you want to understand drifting,
你得了解轮胎
you have to understand tyres,
而这里正是轮胎圣殿
and this place is a tyre temple.
第三 也是最重要的
Third, and most important,
你想要了解轮胎
if you want to know about tyres,
你就得知道如何漂移
you have to know how to drift,
那就是这位老兄的专长
and that is where this chap comes in.
他叫杰罗姆·哈斯林
His name is Jérôme Haslin,
他是米其林的首席轮胎测试员
and he is Michelin's chief tyre tester
专为宝马 保时捷 法拉利和布加迪做测试
for BMW, Porsche, Ferrari and Bugatti.
橡胶在血管中涌动
Rubber compound runs through his veins.
他是抓地力的一代宗师
He is a Zen master of grip,
漂移界的功夫熊猫
a Kung Fu Panda of drifting,
而我是他的小学生
and I am to be his new pupil.
对我们来说 漂移是很严肃的 因为我们要评估轮胎的表现
我们要评估不仅是在极限前或者极限时的表现 还有超越极限后的
这就是他所谓的"超越极限"
This is what he means by "over the limit".
他用动力把车尾甩出线外
He uses power to kick the back of the car out of line...
然后通过精准的油门和转向
and then a delicate balance of throttle and steering
来保持漂移
to keep it there.
你打方向的技巧真是绝了
Your steering-wheel technique is amazing.
我总是和油门踏板嬉戏
I play a lot with the gas pedal.
如果你踩油门熟练了
And if you work a lot with the gas,
你就不需要控制方向盘了
you have nothing to do with the steering.
就可以单手漂移 就像这样
You can do all with one hand, like this.
-所以你在用右脚转向吗 -是的
- So you're steering the car with your right foot? - Yes.
杰罗姆 我学这个太明智了
Jérôme, this is brilliant that I learn how to do this
因为你看到网上的那种
because you read those lists on the Internet
女人欣赏男人的清单 看到过吗
of things that women appreciate in a man, don't you?
里面总会有诚实 正直
And there's always honesty, integrity,
忠诚 忠贞 漂移之类的
loyalty, fidelity, drifting.
总是必要的
It's always there.
到了我学习的时候了
On that note, it was time for me to begin my lesson.
你可以把座椅再调调
You can pull up the seat more.
-怎么调 -更靠近方向盘一点
- More what? - More close to the steering wheel.
你什么意思
What are you trying to say?
好的 那我开始了
OK. So, here we go.
制造转向过度 漂起来了 然后给
Provoking oversteer, coming off, and then feeding...
不 这成了原地打转了
No, and then going round in a small circle.
我的挑战是漂完整的一圈
My challenge was to drift the car for one complete lap.
给油 多打方向
Gas, oversteer.
-松油门 反打方向 -松油门 反打方向
- Release gas, counter-steer. - Release gas, counter-steer.
-噢我原地打转了 -没事
- Oh, I've spun! - OK.
给油 给油 给油
Gas, gas, gas, gas!
噢 妈蛋
Oh, bugger!
没多久 不停的原地打转
Soon, the constant spinning
就开始让我的老师产生了不良反应
started to have an effect on my teacher.
再给一点油 不
A little bit more power. No.
对 松开油门
Yeah, off the gas.
奇怪了 我还以为这很简单的
This is weird. I thought this would be so easy.
-好的 能让我呼吸下新鲜空气吗 -当然
- OK, is it possible to take air? Fresh air? - Yeah.
-因为我马上就要吐了
Because I will be ill in two minutes.
我做的很不好吗
Is this going badly?
当杰罗姆去和他吃过的早饭说拜拜的时候
While Jérôme went off to say hello to his breakfast...
我继续埋头苦练
I continued plugging away.
快速地给油并反打方向
Begin power and begin counter-steer immediately.
然后保持住
Now hold it.
没多久就开始有了好的苗头
And soon, it started to click.
老子现在绝对是在漂移 无可辩驳
What I am doing is drifting. There's no denying that.
是的 就是这样
Oh, yes! Yes!
我的脚已经和方向盘融为一体了
I've connected the steering wheel to my feet.
这是一种全新的体验
This is a whole new feeling.
不是我去应付侧滑
This is not reacting to a slide,
而是故意引起侧滑
this is deliberately provoking it
然后保持在这个状态上
and keeping it right on the point.
哈哈 杰罗姆 你这法国的...(模仿法国口音)
Ha-ha, Jérôme, you French...
指导漂移和滑雪的家伙
drift-and-ski-instructing dude, you.
他会刮目相看的
He'll be impressed with this.
的确
And he was,
所以我们很快进入了
so we immediately progressed
下一个阶段
to the next level.
杰罗姆 在我们开始前
Just before we start, Jérôme,
你真的要让这看起来简单到爆吗
are you going to make this look really annoyingly easy?
你肯定会的 行吧
Yeah, you are. OK.
他的确是这么做的
He did.
这个叫做变向漂移
This is called transitioning--
先漂向一个方向 然后再漂向另一个方向
drifting the car one way and then the other.
做得好的话堪比芭蕾舞般优雅
Get it right and it's almost balletic.
太优美了
That is beautiful.
从这样到这样 无缝衔接
From that to that, seamlessly.
然而 接下来的就不怎么优雅了
Which, sadly, couldn't be said of what followed.
刹车
Brake!
刹车 刹车 刹车
Brake, brake, brake.
噢 该死的
Oh, bollocks.
宝马知道我们用他们的车吗
Does BMW know we're using their car?
-不知道吧 -好吧
- I don't think so. - OK.
终于功夫不负有心人
Eventually, though...
耶
Yeah!
是的 这就是变向漂移
Yes, that was a transition.
你的第一次
Your first.
一天结束 我已经驾轻就熟
By the end of the day, I really had got it mastered.
这是我第一次化身为
I'd become, for the first time,
一位车神
a driving god.
真的
It really is...
当你给油恰到好处
It really is the most amazing feeling
让后轮漂起来的时候
when you get just the right amount of power
那感觉实在太妙了
to spin the back wheels,
但不要给太多油 不然车就要打转了
but not so much that you don't spin the whole car,
要控制在临界点上
and you hold it on the edge.
等会 不好意思 他去法国回来
No, I'm sorry, I'm sorry. He came back from France,
就一天
where he'd spent one day
然后就说 "我现在厉害了"
saying, "Well, I'm brilliant now."
对啊 我就是
Yeah, well, I am.
不是 对不起啊
Well, now, I'm sorry.
哈蒙德 我花了十年时间
Hammond, it took me ten years
才学会如何漂移
to learn how to drift a car.
-嗯哼 -十...
- Mm-hm. Mm-hm. - Ten--
但因为我不是头猩猩
But because I'm not an ape,
我一天就学会了
I did it in one day.
-才没有 -我就是
- You didn't! - Well, I did.
好了好了 这不重要
Look, anyway, it doesn't matter.
为了看看他是不是车神
To find out if he was a driving god,
我和克拉克森为理查德哈蒙德
Clarkson and I arranged for Richard Hammond
安排了一次漂移赛
to take part in a drifting contest.
是的 我们为他准备了车
Yeah, we did. We fixed up the car for him.
也安排好了对手
We fixed up the competitors.
万事俱备
We did everything.
就是这辆车
This is the car.
它原本是一辆日产200SX
It started out as a Nissan 200SX,
但是配备了700马力的6.2升V8引擎
but it's been fitted with a 700-horsepower 6.2L V8
和一个改装的转向器
and a modified steering rack,
所以它能这样
so it can do this.
它的车主 史蒂夫·"巴格西"·比亚乔尼
Its owner, a chap called Steve "Baggsy" Biagioni,
史蒂夫·比亚乔尼 英国职业漂移车手
他说 为了给我的比赛做准备
said that, to prepare for my competition,
我需要在一排标志桶上放上西瓜
I needed to put some melons on a row of traffic cones.
这是要干嘛
What are we doing with these?
我能放下来吗 这些瓜太沉了
Can I put mine down? They're really heavy.
在漂移赛里
Well, in a drifting competition,
有一种近切点
you have what's called clipping points.
Clipping point：漂移车辆需要在1米距离以内漂过该点，失败则扣分
-嗯 -这些点是
- Yes. - So these would be
裁判们在赛道上设置的点
determined points on the track
他们想在那里观察车辆
made by the judges as to where they want to see the car.
-近切点是西瓜吗 -对的 西瓜
- Our clipping points are melons? - Melons, yes.
我的要求是
My orders were to get
尽可能地靠近那些瓜
as close to the melons as possible
但又不撞到它们
without hitting them.
我们要集中注意力
We're just gonna concentrate
寻找赛道的中央位置
on looking for the middle of the track, yeah,
并且把车尾指向瓜的附近
and aim the back of the car near them melons.
好的
OK.
好的 准备好的话就上吧
Right, when you're ready, go for it.
该死的
Bollocks!
我还完全没有掌握技巧...
Having not really mastered this at all...
我的天
Oh, shit!
大猩猩和船长
...it was time for the event
组织的赛事就要开始了
organised by Clarkson and May to begin.
他们告诉我到这儿报到
What they've done is told me to report here,
罗金汉姆赛道
Rockingham Raceway,
在这里他们安排了
where they've arranged for me
我和两位漂移车手
to take on two drifters
一起进行漂移赛
in some competitive drifting.
比赛路线是由一系列经典的变向漂移弯组成
The course was a series of classic transitional bends...
巧妙的布满了
strategically peppered
一些令人生畏的近切点
with the dreaded clipping points.
巴格西要向我解释如何计分
Baggsy was on hand to explain how the scoring worked.
漂移赛是以裁判为核心的运动
The main thing about drifting is that it's a judged sport,
裁判设置近切点的地方就是他们想观察车辆的地方
and the judges have placed the clipping points where they want to see the car.
所以不是车头就是车尾
So that'll either be the rear or the front of the car.
你离近切点越近
The closer you get to the clipping points,
你得的分数就越多
the more points you're gonna get awarded.
但最重要的是不要撞到它们
But the key is to not hit them.
如果你能擦过它们
If you can brush them,
你就能得到最高的分数
you're gonna get maximum points.
我说的"擦过"
When I say "brush",
是要不能把它们撞翻
I mean don't knock them over.
如果你能够
If you can be
保持半米以内的距离
within half a metre,
你就能得高分
you're gonna score high.
我也可以通过保持华丽的漂移
I'd also score points for holding the car
来获取额外的分数
in as impressive a drift as possible.
你还要记住持续给油
You've got to keep the throttle in
就你就可以在漂移的时候保持一个良好的角度
so that you maintain the drift with good angle,
而这只跟你打了多少方向
and that's only up to you about how much steering input
和给了多少油门有关
and how much accelerator you put in.
赛车被设计成能以接近90°角漂移
The cars are designed to run at almost 90°.
它们的转向角非常大
They've got massive amounts of steering angle,
这样直到赛道最后你也可以照样开
so you can drive on the end of your rack.
好的 所以我开得很快的话
OK. So I don't get awarded points
有没有额外的奖励分
for how quickly I do the whole thing?
不 速度没有影响
No, that doesn't come into it.
只有角度和走线才重要
It's all about angle, line,
还有你有多少观赏性
and how much you excite everybody.
就是看谁能秀一脸 是吧
It's judged showing off, isn't it?
-基本上是的 -行吧
- Basically, yeah. - Yeah, OK.
当我的赛车正在为参赛做准备的时候
As my car was prepped for the big event,
我的同事安排的竞争对手
the competitors, organised by my colleagues,
终于来了
finally arrived.
而他们和我想象的不太一样
And they weren't what I was expecting.
看起来詹姆斯和杰里米
It seems James and Jeremy
还是希望他们的老同事能赢的
want their old mate to do well after all,
因为 如果我没看错的话
because, unless I'm mistaken,
我的对手是一个小孩
it would appear that I'm up against a child
还有一个没有胳膊的人
and a man with no arms.
好的
OK.
这就是我今天的比赛
That's my competition.
裁判们已就位
With the judges in position,
比赛就要开始了
it was time for the contest to begin.
首先登场的是这位残疾的先生
First up was the disabled gentleman,
来自波兰的巴泰克·奥斯塔沃斯基
Bartek Ostatowski from Poland.
实际上 巴泰克...
The fact is, Bartek...
他的上肢部分有两处缺陷
is deficient in the arms department to the tune of two.
我说的"缺陷" 我不是指缺陷
When I say "deficient", I don't mean deficient.
他...
He... He has...
他根本就没有上肢
He has no arms... at all.
所以我想说 他能敢于参加已经很了不起了
So, I mean, it's brilliant that he's having a go.
真的 太伟大了
Really, it's tremendous.
巴泰克在一场摩托车事故中失去双臂
Bartek, who lost his arms in a motorcycling accident,
但却克服困难 用脚打方向
overcomes his disability by steering with his foot
并且用肩膀换挡
and changing gear with his shoulder.
对我来说不幸的是 他非常擅长
And unfortunately for me, he's rather good at it.
他是怎么...
How is he...?
好样的
Good for you!
真是好样的
Really good for you!
耶 很好
Yeah! Good!
感觉非常好
This was nice.
满分是30分
Out of a maximum of 30 points,
裁判给了巴泰克22分
the judges awarded Bartek a score of 22.
然后轮到那个小孩了
And then it was the turn of the child,
康纳·夏拿汉 只有13岁
Conor Shanahan, who's just 13 years old.
要来了 康纳的小学生漂移
Here we go. Primary-school drifting with Conor.
他也就开10米就会没兴趣了
He'll go ten yards, get bored,
然后哭着找妈妈
and start crying for his mummy.
然而...
However...
他才13岁啊 还有5年才能有选举权啊
He's 13! I mean, he's five years off voting!
理查德 哈蒙德
年纪比我大了三倍个子还差不多
裁判给了这个嘚瑟的小杂...
The judges awarded the cocky little sh...
小天才27分
talented young man a score of 27.
然后轮到我了
And then it was my turn.
好 胜负在此一举了
Right, this is it.
见证荣耀的时刻
My shot at glory.
我所有的才学
Everything I'd learned
都会展现在聚光灯下
would be brought into sharp focus.
给油 给油 给油
Gas, gas, gas, gas, gas!
最重要的是不要撞到它们
The key is to not hit them.
现在 就是见证奇迹的时刻
Here, in the moment of truth...
我在等黄灯 来了
I'm waiting for amber. There it is.
黄灯然后...
Amber and...
为了Grand Tour荣耀前进的
forward to glory for Grand Tour!
弹离合
Clutch kick!
噢 糟了
Oh, shit!
冲过终点
Oh! And across the line!
耶
Yeah!
耶 我打翻了旗子
Yeah, I clipped the flag.
我想这可能会额外加一分
That's probably an extra point, I imagine.
额...我再点一次火
Erm... I'll just restart,
因为我还想在那儿停一下
because I wanted to stop there for a minute.
是的 噢 我又熄火了
Yep. Oh, I've stalled again.
好的
Yep. Yep.
谢谢大家
Thank you.
所以说...
So...
等一下 你最终得分是多少
Hold on. What was your final score?
两分
Two.
-只有两分 -是的
- Two? - Yes.
你太渣了
You were useless!
不 听着 伙计们
No, listen, gentlemen. Gentlemen.
我必须得说 我很高兴
I have to say, I'm delighted
你已经掌握了漂移技巧 尽管不多
that you now have, albeit limited, drifting skills,
因为这意味着我有了一个玩伴
cos it means I have a playmate,
就像下面这个过去12周的剪辑所展现的
as this short montage from the last 12 weeks shows.
是吧 看到了吗
Yeah, you see?
是的 就在临界点上
Yeah. Yeah. On the edge.
好的 我承认这不是...
Now, I admit... I admit it's not...
这的确不是什么有价值的事
It's not important work, really.
对 我们并没有找到什么疾病的解药
No, we haven't actually cured anything.
我们也没给战乱地区
No, we haven't brought peace
带来和平之类的
to troubled parts of the world or any of that.
是 但这好歹也算个差事
No, but it is a job.
这是个差事 而我们很擅长这个差事
It is a job, and we're very good at it.
-不 你们不擅长 -我们擅长
- No, you're not very good at it. - We are.
不 我这里有几段
No, well, I've got some items
回收站里找到的未播出的镜头
from the unseen footage bin
那上面可不是这么说的
that would suggest otherwise.
很抱歉 我们没时间看了
Unfortunately, we don't have time for that.
可惜 太可惜了
Sadly. Cor, that's a pity!
不 你错了 我们还有时间
No, no. You're wrong. We do have time.
谁想看那些视频吗 没人
Who wants to see that? Nobody.
好的 我们来看
OK. Let's roll it.
这是理查德·哈蒙德
Here is Richard Hammond.
他能驾驭170匹马力吗
Can he contain 170 horsepower?
不 看起来不行
No, it would appear not.
杰里米·克拉克森 保时捷911 GT3
Jeremy Clarkson, Porsche 911 GT3.
好吧 看到了吗
Oh, there we go. You see
我有点玩脱了
I have actually made a mess of that.
是的你玩脱了 我们看见了
Yes, you have, and we saw it.
哈蒙德和留你名弯较劲
Richard Hammond negotiating Your Name Here.
你当时的名字
Your name, in this instance,
显然是大白痴啊
is Total Bell End, it would appear.
大猩猩 他驯服GT3了吗
Clarkson, has he tamed the GT3?
才没有
No!
我有个想法 等着
I've had an idea. Hold on.
我猜你不是这么想的
I bet it wasn't this.
看好了 准备
Watch this. Ready?
千万别立flag
Never say that.
就算你只是开着家用四门轿车
Even if you're just in a four-door family saloon,
也会变成灾难
it's disastrous.
好的 理查德哈蒙德他这回能行了吗
Right, Richard Hammond, has he got it yet?
好的 我觉得他成功了 好的
Yes, I think he has. Yes! Yes!
不 他还是没成功
No. No, he hasn't got it.
-我跟你说 -人无完人
- I tell you what - Nobody's perfect!
-就那么几次 -嗯 大概两次 三次 四次 五次这样
- A couple of moments. - Yeah, just two or three, four, five.
别担心
Don't worry. Don't worry.
以后 我们会找
In the future, we'll just get
一个没胳膊的人和一个小孩来做这些
an armless man and small boy to do those bits.
闭嘴
Shut up! Shut up!
而不是让一个胖子和一个小孩来做是吗
As opposed to a fat man and a small boy.
不管怎样...
Anyway...
听着 在这糟糕的失望中
Listen, on that terrible disappointment,
不仅到了本集节目的结尾
it is time to end not just the show
也到了我们这一季节目的尾声了
but the entire series.
非常感谢大家的观看
Thank you so much for watching.
感谢你们的到来
Thank you all for coming.
今年的晚些时候
And we'll see you later in the year
我们再跟大家见面
for more of this.
大家保重 再见
Take care. Goodbye.